## **Richard Stagg**

## Senior Marketing Planner + Strategist

@: richardstagg97@gmail.com

**雹:** 07521379765

2: 72 Thirlmere Avenue, Tilehurst Reading, RG30 6XN

#### **Profile**

A senior marketing planner with extensive experience working with a wide array of consumer and B2B brands, from niche startups to household-name multinationals. Skilled in developing effective strategies behind compelling and action-driving integrated projects. These have spanned a multitude of formats and executions including campaign, brand building, lead generation, web, app, social, and content – each with their own distinct nuances and challenges to overcome. Recognised by peers for genuine passion, energy and thoughtful approach.

#### **Key Skills**



### Strategic thinking

- Taking strategic lead on high-profile client accounts in planning and implementing multi-channel campaigns
- Getting under the skin of each brief to understand the underlying challenges and identifying potential avenues to solving them
- Keen ability to process, interpret and make recommendations from quantitative and qualitative data sources
- ➡ Harnessing behavioral and market insights to guide and inform the direction of marketing strategies that deliver business-critical actions against objectives
- Creative proposition and messaging development that simplify the complex and inspire creative teams and clients alike
- Detailed knowledge of integrated and multi-channel projects in an agency environment.



# Implementation + execution

- Developing channel and messaging strategies to talk to target audiences in the right place, at the right time and in the right way to ensure ongoing effectiveness
- □ Initial content ideation aligned to audience needs and drivers
- Collaborating with business development teams to create and present proposals and pitches to win new work
- Assisting the creation, development and testing of key brand experiences
- Using multiple analytics platforms (including Google Analytics, Omniture and Buzzsumo) to measure and analyse ongoing project performance; adopting a test-and-learn approach to KPIs.
- A strong commercial mindset when considering any approach taken.



Collaboration

- Working collaboratively and productively with multiple stakeholders, internally and externally, at all levels of seniority
- Building strong relationships with client service, performance and creative teams to deliver high-quality outputs
- Managing positive and productive planning teams, supporting the delivery of wider projects, and nurturing talent
- Overseeing multiple projects of various sizes and scopes to ensure timely delivery that meets and exceeds all expectations
- Experience in commercial and account management teams and roles
- Confident presenting insight and recommendations to internal teams and external clients
- Positive and constructive attitude to working with others.

#### Experience

#### TMW Business

(Unlimited Group) Sept 2018 - Now

## Associate Planning Director (Senior Planner Sep 18 - Oct 2022)

Leading and developing strategic activity underpinning campaigns for a prestigious roster of predominantly B2B tech and SaaS clients. These include Microsoft, Fujitsu, Capita and Poly. In this integrated role I work across multiple programmes including account-based marketing (ABM), lead and revenue generation, brand development, channel and customer marketing. This requires varied channel use, including online and offline channels including digital, direct, content, social and paid media to simplify the complex and bring compelling propositions to life.

## August Media

#### Strategist

## (Publicis Groupe)

Sep 2013 - Sep 2018

As a strategist specialising in editorial brand content, the key responsibilities were to deliver actionable research; using it to build clear, defined recommendations and helping relevant stakeholders develop and implement smart multi-channel content proposals. Working across the entire client portfolio, including flagship projects for *Honda*, *IKEA*, *Renault*, *Ocado*, *Heineken* and *Hiscox*.

#### Redwood

## Account Manager

# (Omnicom Group)

Nov 2012 - Aug 2013

This position involved running the day-to-day operations of a global print and digital customer title for Mazda, including markets in New Zealand, Netherlands and off-shore developing markets. This extended to implementing, measuring and analysing performance of new and innovative content platforms.

#### Seven

#### Account Executive

#### (Guardian Media Group)

Mar 2012 - Nov 2012

Working with the group publishing director and commercial team to manage Seven's largest B2B account, the Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA). The core function was to assist with the management and delivery of cross-media campaigns of varying scope for third-party clients. It required balancing the demands of the main client and the array of requirements from key stakeholders in several relationships.

#### Seven

#### Business Development Executive

#### (Guardian Media Group)

Jul 2010 - Mar 2012

Supporting the head of business development in prospecting, tendering and pitching for new clients for content agency Seven. This varied role involved working with diverse teams to produce timely, smart pitches and supporting materials, as well as working across the entire account portfolio which included Waterstones, Sainsbury's, Weight Watchers and Virgin.

#### **Education**

BA (Hons) Marketing Management	Kingston University	2007 – 2010
3 A-levels (Maths, Geography, Business Studies)	Charters Sixth Form	2005 – 2007
10 GCSEs	Charters School, Sunningdale	2000 – 2005

#### Other interests

- Dystopian novels
- Immersive technology
- Modern boardgaming
- Αl

- Tabletop roleplaying
- Camping and hiking

#### References

Available on request.